# Mo Zhai

150 E Schiller Street Apt 505 Elmhurst IL 60126

E-mail: <u>mozhai@live.com</u> web: <u>www.zhaimobile.com</u>

Phone: (773)678-3620

#### Me

I am an experienced software engineer with over 4 years of professional experience. My experience covers development using Objective C, Java, .NET, C++, Javascript, and many other languages on top of most popular frameworks. I have delivered several enterprise web applications as well as mobile apps for business in both iOS App Store and Android Play Store. I am a hard worker with great leaning skills, and I have an enthusiastic heart for IT industry.

#### **Education**

#### **DePaul University**

Graduation March, 2012

Master of Science in **Computer Game Development**, Graduate School of College of Computing and Digital Media GPA=3.98

# **Tianjin Normal University**

Graduation July, 2007

Bachelor's degree in **Computer Engineering**, emphasis on Information Engineering GPA=3.21 First rank scholarship

# **Experience**

**Software Engineer** @ Echelon Consulting, L.L.C.

5/2012 - now

- iOS and Android development for app stores, using Objective C, and Java
- Backed-end development using C#, Lucene.net and Python for mobile apps
- Business web application development using Liferay, Java, Dojo, and .Net

**Software developer internships**@ Space to Play

2/2012 - 4/2012

• Creating a 3Ds Max plug-in in C++, which facilitates editing and visualization of urban 3D building models from geo-spatial database (PostGIS).

Graduate Assistant and Tech support @ CDM, DePaul University

01/2011 - 03/2012

• Daily Maintaining and management for labs of the College CDM. Preparing software and equipments for professors.

Network Engineer @ China TieTong- Equipment Center

08/2007 - 03/2009

- Analyzing, and refining the central node of the company PSTN network.
- Tools and scripts development for internal use.

#### Skills

- Frameworks: iOS, Android, Liferay, ASP.Net MVC, J2EE, Dojo, Lucene.Net, OpenGL
- Language: Objective C, Java, JavaScript, C++, C#, Python, SQL
- IDE: Visual Studio, Xcode, Eclipse, and etc.
- Platforms: MacOS X, Windows, Linux

#### **Project List**

**SIDLEY mobile for iOS** 

Capacity: Objective C, Cocoa touch, Core Data

**Responsibility**: Took part in development Sidley marketing app for iOS5/6, and in charge of development brand new iOS7/8 app with flat-design. The app supports both iPhone and iPad, and it is optimized for iPhone 6/6plus by using auto-layout storyboard. In the app, dynamic contents are synced from proxy server and persisted in Core Data. Uls render updated data such as news, bio info, location info and other interests. This app also supports topics and people searching.

**App store link**: <a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/sidley-mobile/id574510600">https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/sidley-mobile/id574510600</a>

#### **Project List**

### SIDLEY mobile apps backend

Capacity: Asp.Net, Lucene.net, Python

**Responsibility:** In charge of development of the searching APIs for SIDLY mobile. A standalone C# and Python application firstly pre-processes target documents, and then it uses Lucene.net to create full-text index of processed data. The .Net proxy server finally uses this index to dynamically create ranked topic list by comparing the similarities between grouped documents and input. In charge of development of the location APIs for mobile app. The .Net based proxy server caches dynamic location info every few hours by querying Google Place API with given criteria. Then the server uses caches location data to fulfill mobile app requests in JSON.

In charge of development push-notification service in C# for Android GCM.

Took part in the development of the documents sync service on top of SQL Server database. CRUD operations on management pages lead to contents sync and notification push in mobile app.

#### **SIDLEY mobile for Android**

Capacity: Java, Android UI, SQLite

**Responsibility:** In charge of development Sidley marketing android app from scratch to Play store. including testing, and deployment. The app is targeted from android 2.2. to 4.2, and it is based on fragment/activity UIs for both phone and tablet. Dynamic contents are synced from proxy server and persisted in local SQLite database. A new created ePub reader renders document based contents and a customized webView displays bio info of people in Sidley.

Play store link: https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.sidley.sidleymobile.android

#### Atkearney.com Portal web site 6.2

Capacity: Java, Javascript, Dojo, Liferay, Python, CSS, Responsive Design

**Responsibility**: Took part in the portal migrations from Liferay 6.1 to 6.2. Created javascript widgets to replace old Jsp contents. Developed and updated portlets and hooks for customized web Uls and functionalities. Created a distributable similarity comparing tools in python and writing Beanshell scrips to support auto translation for more than 20 different country sites. Also working on portal theme updating to apply responsive design.

Link: http://www.atkearney.com/

# SIDLEY Doc Enterprise iOS App for Good Dynamic

Capacity: Objective C, C#, Good security (<a href="https://www1.good.com/secure-mobility-solution/">https://www1.good.com/secure-mobility-solution/</a>)

Responsibility: Developed an highly secured mobile app for sensitive documents using Good SDK. In charge of data persistence migration from unsafe PList to encrypted Good CoreData in mobile app. Took part in the development of the file explorer like UI with CRUD and searching supported. In charge of app updating from iOS SDK5 to 8 as long as Good SDK updating from 1.2 to 1.10.

#### Staffing availabilities Intranet project

Capacity: Javascript, dGrid, Dojo, JSP, Llferay

**Responsibility**: In charge of the development for a one-page web Intranet application to visualize staffing availabilities data. The web application sends async request to get data from backend server and saves the data to dStore. An Excel styled grid smoothly renders availabilities data in cells with column locking and scrolling. This web application also supports sorting, filleting and Excel exporting with multi-select dropdown widgets.

## A.T. Kearney: Ideas and Insights for iOS

Capacity: Objective C, Cocoa touch, LinkedIn API, PushSharp

**Responsibility:** In charge of flat-design UI reimplementation, YouTube video playback, backend notification server updating, and social network integration. In the app, users can read or watch latest insights contents and post their opinions to Goole Plus, LinkedIn, Facebook, and twitter. **App store link:** https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/a.t.-kearney-ideas-insights/id506749703

#### A.T. Kearney IMO Intranet project (Current Project)

Capacity: Asp.net MVC, Javascript, Razor

**Responsibility**: Developing a financial web applications for merging cases using ASP.net MVC framework. In charge of setting up the app infrastructure including sql server database connections, entity framework, and javascript libraries. Implementing the web application layout, functionality and UIs of each web page for the business logic.